Tushyap Bari

LinkedIn | Github

Location: Noida, UP, India Email: baritushyap9120@gmail.com | Mobile: 7905389142

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

An enthusiastic developer with experience in **ReactJS**, **JavaScript**, **Java**, **Spring Boot**, **DBMS and AWS**. Self-driven innovator with excellent Leadership and Management capabilities. A result driven professional with uncompromising work ethics acquired around 2 years of experience in the software development industry.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages : JavaScript, Java, SQL

Technologies : React.js, Redux-Toolkit, Bootstrap, Material-UI, Tailwind CSS, HTML5, CSS3, Spring Boot

Databases : MySQL, MongoDB

AWS : S3, Athena, CloudWatch, Glue

Dev Tools : Git, GitHub, Bitbucket, Postman, Jira, Tidal, Notepad++,

iDE : Visual Studio Code, Eclipse, Spring Tool Suite

EXPERIENCE

Associate Software Engineer (React Developer)

June 2022 – Present

GlobalLogic - A Hitachi Group Company

Location – Noida, Uttar Pradesh, India

- Worked with React.js, Various JS Libraries, JavaScript, Rest APIs, MySQL to develop robust and scalable Frontends.
- Troubleshoot and **fixed bugs** and issues to ensure **smooth operation** of the applications.
- Explored Data Engineering Data Processing, ETL and monitored tidal jobs to ensure smooth BAU operations.

Associate Software Engineer (React Developer)

Nov 2021 - May 2022

Ecera System LLC

Location – Ghazipur, Uttar Pradesh, India

- Designed and developed dynamic and responsive webapps using MERN React.js, JavaScript, HTML, CSS.
- Worked with **REST APIs** to retrieve and display data from databases.

EDUCATION

Arya College Of Engineering and Research Center

B.Tech in Electrical Engineering

Jaipur, Rajasthan, India July 2018 – June 2022

CGPA : 9.2

PROJECTS

Associate Software Engineer

July 2023 - Present

GlobalLogic - A Hitachi Group Company

- Develop the new functionality and features as per the requirement also maintain the documentation.
- Coordinate with team and discuss technical problems, Bugs and report the daily status to Reporting Manager
- Worked with React.js,Redux Toolkit, Various JS Libraries, JavaScript, Rest APIs, Bootstrap, Tailwind css, MySQL to develop robust and scalable Frontends.
- Troubleshoot and fixed bugs and issues to ensure smooth operation of the applications.

Associate Software Engineer

Dec 2022 - May 2023

GlobalLogic - A Hitachi Group Company

- Explored Data Engineering Data Processing, ETL using Python Script and monitored tidal jobs to ensure smooth BAU operations.
- Coordinate with team and discuss technical problems, bugs and report the daily status to Reporting Manager.
- · Worked with Python, Pandas, SQL, Tidal, AWS S3, Athena, DynamoDB, CloudWatch, Glue.

• Data Ingestion, Fixed Bugs, monitored tidal jobs to ensure smooth BAU operations.

Trainee Software Engineer

GlobalLogic - A Hitachi Group Company

- Flight Management System :- Spring Boot, Microservices, MySQL, Git, Postman, Swagger.
- Java based application allows Travellers to book, cancel, view and update their bookings with ease.
- All the bookings, flights, schedules and routes can be viewed, added and modified by the administrator.
- My key responsibility was design ER diagram and develop backend using Microservices, Springboot.

Associate Software Engineer

Nov 2021 - May 2022

June 2022 - Nov 2022

Ecera System LLC

- Designed and developed a E-Learning web application which provides courses similar to Udemy, Coding Ninjas.
- My responsibility was develop responsive web pages using React, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS and writing API.
- Worked with **REST APIs** to retrieve and display data from databases using Node Express.

ACHIEVEMENTS / CERTIFICATION

- GATE Qualified: AIR 11340
- 300+ Problems Solved On GFG and Hacker Rank
- Excellence Certification of Java from Coding Ninjas.
- Certification of Creativity at Ecera System LLC.